A Guide to the Ford Foundation records, Peace and Social Justice Division (PSJ), Governance and Civil Society, Program Officer, Office Files of Michael Lipsky FA595
Rockefeller Archive Center
- State Fiscal Analysis Initiative, 1991-2003; 3
  - William Cartier, Alex Wilde, 1994 (Box 22, Folder 197)
  - David Chiel, 1994 (Box 22, Folder 198)
  - Terrence George - Manila, 1994-1996 (Box 22, Folder 199)
  - John Gerhart, 1994-1995 (Box 22, Folder 200)
  - Jonathan Hecht, 1994 (Box 23, Folder 201)
  - Kim Krasevac - Mexico, 1994 (Box 23, Folder 202)
  - Joseph Schull, 1994 (Box 23, Folder 203)
  - Bradford Smith - Brazil, 1994 (Box 23, Folder 204)
  - Kenneth Wilson - Harare, 1994 (Box 23, Folder 205)
  - Bob Wilson - Lyndon B. Johnson School of Public Affairs, University of Texas, 1994 (Box 23, Folder 206)
  - International Workshop on Exemplary Local Governance, 1995 (Box 23, Folder 207)
  - Workshop on Local Practice, 1994-1995 (Box 23, Folder 208)
  - Professor Robert Wilson, University of Texas, 1994 (Box 23, Folder 209)
  - State Fiscal Analysis Initiative - Renewal Notes, 1998 (Box 23, Folder 210)
  - Arkansas Advocates for Children and Families - Proposal, 1998 (Box 23, Folder 211)
  - Colorado Children's Campaign - Proposal, 1998 August (Box 23, Folder 212)
  - Colorado Center on Law and Policy, 1997-1998 (Box 23, Folder 213)
  - Indiana Coalition on Housing and Homeless Issues - Proposal, 1998 (Box 24, Folder 214)
  - Voices for Connecticut's Children - Proposal, 1997-1998 (Box 24, Folder 215-217)
  - Citizens for Missouri's Children - Proposal, 1998 (Box 24, Folder 218)
  - Kentucky Youth Advocates - Proposal, 1998 (Box 24, Folder 219)
  - Kansas Action for Children - Proposal, 1998 (Box 24, Folder 220)
  - Association for Children of New Jersey - Proposal, 1998 (Box 25, Folder 221)
  - Children's Defense Fund - Ohio - Proposal, 1998 (Box 25, Folder 222-224)
  - Basic State Fiscal Analysis Initiative File, 1993-1998 (Box 25, Folder 225)
- Innovations in State and Local Government Files, 1985-2003; 4
  Biographical / Historical
  In 1986, the Ford Foundation, with the assistance of the John F. Kennedy School of Government at Harvard University, initiated an awards program on Innovations in State and Local Government. The objective of the program was to demonstrate that American governments are capable of responding creatively and effectively to critical social issues. Each winning program received a Foundation grant of $100,00 to disseminate information about the program and encourage its replication. From 1986 until 1995 (with a hiatus in 1989), the awards honored ten states, cities, counties, and tribal or public authorities for exemplary innovative programs. In 1995, the Foundation expanded the number of $100,000 awards from ten to 15 and began honoring federal Innovations as well. The program was renamed Innovations in American Government at this time and began partnering with the Council for Excellence in Government.
  The Foundation undertook a variety of outreach activities in support of the Innovations Program. It hired a public relations firm to disseminate information about award-winners, finalists, and semi-finalists, and to promote awareness of the program in the popular media and trade press. It sponsored a program booklet to publicize Innovations programs. The ceremony was held in D.C. beginning in 1993. Between 1993 and 1998, Vice President Albert Gore participated in the event.
  - Innovations in State and Local Government Awards Program - Press Releases Regarding Creation of Program, 1985-1988 (Box 25, Folder 226)
  - The 1988 Innovations in State and Local Government Awards Program Public Relations Activity Report, Public Interest Public Relations (PIPR), 1988 November (Box 25, Folder 227)
  - Innovations Conference, "Diffusion of Innovations in the Public Sector" (Austin, Texas), 1989 September 14-16 (Box 25, Folder 228)
  - Innovations Office of Communications (FY 1990), 1989 (Box 25, Folder 229)
  - Awards - Finalists' Presentations (Cambridge, MA), 1990 July 12-13 (Box 25, Folder 230)
  - Reports, Memoranda, and Planning Documents, 1987-1991 (Box 26, Folder 231)
  - Awards Program Booklets, 1986-1991 (Box 26, Folder 232)
  - Publication - Updates 1992: Innovations in State and Local Government, 1986-1992 (Box 26, Folder 233)
  - Call for Applications, 1990-1991 (Box 26, Folder 234)
  - Research on Innovations in State and Local Government Booklet for the 1991 Conferences at Duke University and the University of Washington (Box 26, Folder 235)
    Conference 1: "The Fundamental Questions of Innovation," Duke University
    Conference 2: "Innovation and the Media: Stimulus or Barrier?" University of Washington
  - Brochure - Innovating America: A Video About How to Create and Manage Government, From the Ford Foundation and the John F. Kennedy School of Government at Harvard University, 1990 (Box 26, Folder 236)
  - Innovating America: A Video About How to Create and Manage Government, From the Ford Foundation and the John F. Kennedy School of Government at Harvard University, 1990; VHS (Box 1, Tape AV 13016)
    Access copy currently unavailable. Please contact a RAC archivist for further instruction.
    Part one: "Creating Change"; Part two: "Sustaining Change": Two-part video presents ways to stimulate and implement new approaches to different government problems, and suggests ways to improve the performance of public managers across the nation." (Text from original tape container packaging.)
  - Governing Magazine Anniversary Issues, 1988-1990 (Box 26, Folder 237)
  - Governing Magazine, 1991 (Box 26, Folder 238)
  - Governing Magazine, 1993-1994 (Box 26, Folder 239)
  - Governing Magazine - Lipsky Final Approval of Fall 1998 Issue (Box 26, Folder 240)
  - Governing Magazine - Michael Lipsky's Op Ed Piece - North Carolina Smart Start Ushers in a New Generation of Governing, 1993-1999 (Box 27, Folder 241)
  - Innovations 1992 - Budget, 1992 Meeting Issue Memos (Box 27, Folder 242)
  - Innovations 1992 - Program Book, Presentation Schedules and Materials, and Correspondence (Box 27, Folder 243)
  - Innovations 1993 - Clipbook (Press), 1993-1994 (Box 27, Folder 244)
  - Innovations 1993, ¼ inch audio cassette (Box 1, Tape AV 15818)
  - Innovations 1993 - List of Award Recipients, 1986-1993 (Box 27, Folder 245)
  - Innovations 1993 - Newspaper Clippings and Correspondence with Finalists (Box 27, Folder 246)
  - Innovations 1993 - Vice President Albert Gore, Jr. and White House Participation (Box 27, Folder 247)
  - Innovations 1993 - Application Pamphlet (Box 27, Folder 248)
  - Innovations 1993 - Public Relations, M. Booth and Associates, 1992-1993 (Box 27, Folder 249)
  - Innovations 1993 - Recommendations for Grant Actions (Box 27, Folder 250)
  - Innovations 1994 - Trustee Meeting, 1994 March (Box 28, Folder 251)
  - Innovations 1994 - June Letter - National Selection Committee (Box 28, Folder 252)
  - Innovations 1994 - Logistics for Innovations Award Event in D.C., 1994 September 29 (Box 28, Folder 253)
  - Innovations 1994 - Old Executive Office Building Reception - Awards Event (Box 28, Folder 254)
  - Innovations 1994 - Awards Event - Washington, D.C. Planning (Box 28, Folder 255)
  - Innovations 1994 - Awards Event - Innovations and the White House/Al Gore Invitation (Box 28, Folder 256)
  - Innovations 1994 - Awards Event - Guest List Development - Ford Foundation Colleagues (Box 28, Folder 257)
  - Innovations 1994 - Awards Event - Invitation Card (Box 28, Folder 258)
  - Innovations 1994 - Awards Event - Thank You Letters - National Selection Committee (Box 28, Folder 259)
  - Innovations 1994 - Awards Event - Memoranda to Susan V. Berresford and Franklin Thomas Regarding Event Planning (Box 28, Folder 260)
  - Innovations 1994 - Awards Event - Franklin Thomas Letters to CEOs of Winning Proposals (Box 28, Folder 261)
  - Innovations 1994 - Awards Event - Congress Invited to Awards Event (Box 28, Folder 262)
  - Innovations 1994 - Awards Event - Special Dinner Request (Box 28, Folder 263)
  - Innovations 1994 - Awards Event - Response List (Box 28, Folder 264)
  - Innovations 1994 - Awards Event - Request for Names for Invitations - Government Organizations (Box 28, Folder 265)
  - Innovations 1994 - M. Booth and Associates - Press Materials and Updates (Box 28, Folder 266)
  - Innovations 1994 - Press Releases (M. Booth and Associates) (Box 28, Folder 267, Box 29, Folder 268)
  - Innovations 1994 - Public Outreach and Dissemination Strategies (Box 29, Folder 269)
  - Innovations 1994 - Communications Strategy, 1993-1994 (Box 29, Folder 270)
  - Innovations 1994 - Worldwide Activities (Box 29, Folder 271)
  - Innovations 1994 - Semi-Finalists (Box 29, Folder 272)
  - Innovations 1994 - Letters to All 25 Innovation Finalists Regarding Guidelines and Current-Rutledge Schedule, 1994 May (Box 29, Folder 273)
  - Innovations 1994 - Guidelines for Finalists (Box 29, Folder 274)
  - Innovations 1994 - Finalists Seminar (Box 29, Folder 275)
  - Innovations 1994 - Award Winners - Guidelines for the $100,000 Award Winners (Box 29, Folder 276)
  - Innovations 1994 - Congratulation Letters to $100,000 Winners (Box 29, Folder 277)
  - Innovations 1994 - Congratulation Letters to Finalists (Box 29, Folder 278)
  - Innovations 1994 - Winners List (Box 29, Folder 279)
  - Innovations 1994 - $100,000 Winners - Coles Levee Ecosystem Preserve (Box 29, Folder 280)
  - Innovations 1994 - $100,000 Winners - Quick Court System (Box 29, Folder 281)
  - Innovations 1994 - $100,000 Winners - Citywide Central Insurance Program (Box 29, Folder 282)
  - Innovations 1994 - $100,000 Winners - Partnership for Long Term Care (Box 29, Folder 283)
  - Innovations 1994 - $100,000 Winners - Voluntary Investigation and Cleanup (Box 29, Folder 284)
  - Innovations 1994 - $100,000 Winners - Sexual Assault Nurse Examiners Program (Box 29, Folder 285)
  - Innovations 1994 - $100,000 Winners - Minnesota Parents' Fair Share (Box 29, Folder 286)
  - Innovations 1994 - $100,000 Winners - Here, Thayer and Everywhere (Box 29, Folder 287)
  - Innovations 1994 - $100,000 Winners - Student Conflict Resolution Experts (Box 29, Folder 288)
  - Innovations 1994 - $100,000 Winners - Oregon Progress Board (Box 30, Folder 289)
  - Innovations 1994 - $20,000 Finalists - Grant Proposals and Memoranda (Box 30, Folder 290)
  - Innovations 1994 - $20,000 Finalists - Community Intensive Supervision Program (Box 30, Folder 291)
  - Innovations 1994 - $20,000 Finalists - CARE/Project HOME AIDS Program (Box 30, Folder 292)
  - Innovations 1994 - $20,000 Finalists - Regional Alliance for Small Contractors (Box 30, Folder 293)
  - Innovations 1994 - $20,000 Finalists - Peer Intervention Program (Box 30, Folder 294)
  - Innovations 1994 - $20,000 Finalists - Project Care (Box 30, Folder 295)
  - Innovations 1994 - $20,000 Finalists - Self-Help Support Systems (Box 30, Folder 296)
  - Innovations 1994 - $20,000 Finalists - Florida Marine Spill Analysis System (Box 30, Folder 297)
  - Innovations 1994 - $20,000 Finalists - Miracle Village (Box 30, Folder 298)
  - Innovations 1994 - $20,000 Finalists - Living in Family Environment (Box 30, Folder 299)
  - Innovations 1994 - $20,000 Finalists - Families and Schools Together (Box 30, Folder 300)
  - Innovations 1994 - $20,000 Finalists - Financial Institutions eXpert eXaminations (Box 30, Folder 301)
  - Innovations 1994 - $20,000 Finalists - Technology Enhanced Community Problem Solving Policing Model (Box 30, Folder 302)
  - Innovations 1994 - $20,000 Finalists - Building Community Campaign (Box 30, Folder 303)
  - Innovations 1994 - $20,000 Finalists - Self-Directed Highway Maintenance Teams (Box 30, Folder 304)
  - Innovations 1994 - $20,000 Finalists - Child Health Clinics (Box 30, Folder 305)
  - Ford Foundation Report Publication Featuring Innovations Program - Fall 1994 (Box 30, Folder 306)
  - Innovations Focus Groups (Federal Component) and Report, "Assessing the Expansion of the Innovations Program to the Federal Level", 1994 (Box 30, Folder 307)
  - Current-Rutledge Video Production - Innovations Film and Media Projects, 1993-1994 (Box 30, Folder 308)
  - Current-Rutledge Video Production - Innovations 1994 (Box 30, Folder 309)
  - Innovations Awards - 1995 Application (Box 31, Folder 310)
  - Innovations 1995 - Press (Box 31, Folder 311)
  - Quality Practices in the Public Sector: A New Institutionalism View of the Diffusion of Innovation, Linda Kaboolian, Harvard University, 1997 (Box 31, Folder 312)
  - Innovations - International - Reports and Materials Regarding Ford Foundation-Funded Programs, 1998-2002 (Box 31, Folder 313)
  - Innovations - International (Harvard Project on American Indian Economic Development), 1999-2000 (Box 31, Folder 314)
  - Innovations - International - "Citizenship, Citizen Participation and Democratic Culture" by David Arnold - Prepared for the Worldwide Governance Meeting (Brazil), 1996 October 18 (Box 31, Folder 315)
  - Innovations - International - "Improving American Governance: Problems and Strategies," Prepared for June 1985 Board of Trustees Meeting (Report 010413), 1985 June (Box 31, Folder 316)
  - Innovations - Materials, 1999-2000 (Box 31, Folder 317)
  - Innovations, 1999 (Box 31, Folder 318)
  - Notes on Innovations, 1998-2000 (Box 31, Folder 319)
  - Harvard University - Institute for Government Innovation Proposal, 2000 (Box 31, Folder 320)
  - Harvard University - Institute for Government Innovation - Grant Documents, 2000-2003 (Box 32, Folder 321)
  - Harvard University - Innovations in American Government Program Proposal, 2000 (Box 32, Folder 322)
  - Harvard University - Institute for Government Innovation and Innovation in American Government Program, 1998-2001 (Box 32, Folder 323)
  - Harvard University - Institute for Government Innovation - Gail Christopher - Status Reports, Memoranda and Reports Regarding Endowment, 2001 (Box 32, Folder 324)
  - Harvard University - Institute for Government Innovation - Brochure and Program Materials, 2001 (Box 32, Folder 325)
  - Harvard University - Innovations in American Government - Andrew Lee, Council for Excellence and Harvard/Kennedy School, 2001 (Box 32, Folder 326)
  - Harvard University - Innovations in American Government - 2001 Finalists Events (Box 32, Folder 327)
  - Innovations Film Project - Innovations Program 10th Anniversary, 1995 (Box 32, Folder 328)
  - Innovations Film Project - Ambrica Productions, 1995 (Box 32, Folder 329)
  - Innovations Film Project - Blackside, 1995 (Box 32, Folder 330)
  - Innovations Film Project - Current-Rutledge, 1995 (Box 32, Folder 331)
  - Innovations Film Project - Dick Young Productions, Ltd., 1995 (Box 33, Folder 332)
  - Innovations Film Project - FireThorn Productions, 1995 (Box 33, Folder 333)
  - Innovations Film Project - Gail Pellett Productions, 1995 (Box 33, Folder 334)
  - Innovations Film Project - Hedrick Smith Productions, Inc., 1995 (Box 33, Folder 335)
    Related Materials
    A VHS titled Across the River - A Community Dialogue with Hedrick Smith was separated from this collection and moved to Ford Foundation records, Audiovisual materials (FA750), 1995 Box 1, Tape AV 10006
  - Innovations Film Project - Midnight Films, 1995 (Box 33, Folder 336)
  - Innovations Film Project - Northern Light Productions, 1995 (Box 33, Folder 337)
  - Innovations 1995 Reception - Franklin Thomas and William Milliken Speeches (Box 33, Folder 338)
  - Innovations 1995 Speeches Docs - Press and Awards (Box 33, Folder 338)
  - Innovations 1995 Reception - Invitation List (Box 33, Folder 339)
  - Innovations 1995 Recommendation for Grant Action (Winners and Finalists) (Box 33, Folder 340)
  - Innovations 1995 - Awards Letters (Box 33, Folder 341)
  - Innovations 1995 Winners and Finalists - City of Tampa - Hillsboro County Health Care Plan (Box 33, Folder 342)
  - Innovations 1995 Winners and Finalists - City of Boulder - Genesis: Healthy Young Families (Box 33, Folder 343)
  - Innovations 1995 Winners and Finalists - City of Albany - Center for Technology in Government (Box 33, Folder 344)
  - Innovations 1995 Winners and Finalists - City of Indianapolis - Competition and Costing (Box 33, Folder 345)
  - Innovations 1995 Winners and Finalists - City of San Antonio - Project Quest (Box 33, Folder 346)
  - Innovations 1995 Winners and Finalists - City of Boston - Elder Choice (Box 33, Folder 347)
  - Innovations 1995 Winners and Finalists - City of New York - Civil Enforcement Initiative (Box 33, Folder 348)
  - Innovations 1995 Winners and Finalists - City of Louisville - CityWork (Box 33, Folder 349)
  - Innovations 1995 Winners and Finalists - City of Shreveport - Hamilton Terrace Learning Center (Box 33, Folder 350)
  - Innovations 1995 Winners and Finalists - City of Seattle - Catalist (Box 33, Folder 351)
  - Innovations 1995 Winners and Finalists - City of Madison - Recruiting the Best and the Brightest (Box 33, Folder 352)
  - Innovations 1995 Winners and Finalists - Salt Lake City - Utah Arts Endowment Fund (Box 33, Folder 353)
  - Innovations 1995 Winners and Finalists - City of Honolulu, Hawaii - FYI (Box 33, Folder 354)
  - Innovations 1995 Winners and Finalists - City of Grand Forks, North Dakota - Advanced Weather Information (Box 33, Folder 355)
  - Innovations 1995 Winners and Finalists - City of Apple Valley, Minnesota - The Ramp Project (Box 33, Folder 356)
  - Innovations 1995 Winners and Finalists - City of Sacramento, California - California Drought Water Bank (Box 33, Folder 357)
  - Innovations 1995 Winners and Finalists - City of Sacramento, California - California Foodlink (Box 33, Folder 358)
  - Innovations 1995 Winners and Finalists - City of Mineola, New York - Recidivist Alcohol Probationer (Box 33, Folder 359)
  - Innovations 1995 Winners and Finalists - City of New York - Red Light Camera Program (Box 33, Folder 360)
  - Innovations 1995 Winners and Finalists - City of Austin - Volunteer Interpreter Service (Box 33, Folder 361)
  - Innovations 1995 - Proposal Guidelines for the Use of $20,000 Grants (Box 33, Folder 362)
  - Innovations 1995 - Proposal Guidelines for the Use of $100,000 Grants (Box 33, Folder 363)
  - Innovations 1995 Public Relations - Press Clippings (Box 33, Folder 364)
  - Innovations 1995 Public Relations - Current/Rutledge Guidelines (Box 33, Folder 365)
  - Innovations 1995 Public Relations - Press Releases (Box 33, Folder 366)
  - Innovations 1995 Public Relations - Post-Event Press Clippings (Box 33, Folder 367)
  - Innovations 1995 - National Selection Committee Names and Addresses (Box 33, Folder 368)
  - Innovations 1995 - National Selection Committee List (Box 33, Folder 369)
  - Innovations 1995 - Lipsky's Letters to Federal Winners, 1995 August 30 (Box 33, Folder 370)
  - Innovations 1995 - Franklin Thomas Letters to Federal Winners, 1995 August 18 (Box 34, Folder 371)
  - Innovations 1995 - Committee Members' Reminder Letter (Box 34, Folder 372)
  - Innovations 1995 - Winners Schedule of the Day Letter (Box 34, Folder 373)
  - Innovations 1995 - Design Copy and Text for Brochure (Box 34, Folder 374)
  - Innovations 1995 - Letters to New National Selection Committee Members (Box 34, Folder 375-376)
  - Innovations 1995 - General File (Box 34, Folder 377)
  - Innovations 1995 - Franklin Thomas Letter (Box 34, Folder 378)
  - Innovations 1995 - Franklin Thomas Letter to Vice President Al Gore - Invitation to Press Briefing (Box 34, Folder 379)
  - Innovations 1995 - Letters to Finalists, 1995 July (Box 34, Folder 380)
  - Innovations 1995 - Letters to Award Winners, 1995 July (Box 34, Folder 381)
  - Innovations 1995 - Harvard University Correspondence (Box 34, Folder 382)
  - Innovations 1995 - Correspondence and Press Releases from M. Booth and Associates (Box 34, Folder 383-385)
  - Innovations Award Program Planning, 1991 (Box 34, Folder 386)
  - Glantz, Gina - Communications Initiative Phase I, 1994-2002 (Box 34, Folder 387-388, Box 35, Folder 389-390)
  - Glantz, Gina - Communications Initiative Phase II, 1996-1997 (Box 35, Folder 391-392)
  - Innovations 1996 - Australia (Box 35, Folder 393)
  - Innovations Public Opinion Research - Assessing Voters' Reactions to Innovations in Government, 1995 November (Box 35, Folder 394)
  - Innovations in American Government, Communication Recommendations, Manning, Selvage, and Lee, 1997 February (Box 35, Folder 395-396)
  - Innovations in American Government - General Documents and Press Clippings, 1995-1997 (Box 35, Folder 397)
  - Innovations 1997 - Renaissance Mayflower Hotel (Box 35, Folder 398)
  - Innovations 1997 - India (Box 35, Folder 399)
  - Innovations 1997 - Innovations International, 1996-1997 (Box 35, Folder 400)
  - Innovations 1997 - Manning, Selvage, and Lee Weekly Report (Box 36, Folder 401)
  - Innovations 1997 - Bill Parent Emerging Trends Memo (Box 36, Folder 402)
  - Innovations 1997 - Semifinalists Press Release (Box 36, Folder 403)
  - Innovations - Other Programs, 1992-2000 (Box 36, Folder 404)
  - Innovations 1997 - Public Opinion (Box 36, Folder 405)
  - Innovations 1997 - Schedules, Correspondence, and Reports (Box 36, Folder 406)
  - Civil Society Meeting - London, 1997 June 3-4 (Box 36, Folder 407)
  - Innovations - Ford Foundation Evaluators List, circa 1996 (Box 36, Folder 408)
  - Innovations 1997 - Booklet (Box 36, Folder 409)
  - Innovations 1996 - Press Releases (Box 36, Folder 410)
  - Innovations 1997 - Innovations Finalists (Box 36, Folder 411)
  - Innovations - Newspaper Articles, 1994-1998 (Box 36, Folder 412)
  - Local Innovations in Health Care Conference, 2000 June 28-30 (Box 37, Folder 413)
  - History of Innovations Program - Memo, 1995 (Box 37, Folder 414)
- Program Related Investment (PRIs) and Finance Related Files, 1959-1995; 5
  The Ford Foundation made its first Program-Related Investment in September 1968. PRIs take the form of loans, guarantees, and equity. These investments are directly aligned with a foundation's programmatic commitments and must meet legal charitable standards.
  - Social Business Venture Study and Meeting at Ford Foundation, 1989 October (Box 37, Folder 415)
  - PRI Issues Papers - Background, 1959-1987 (Box 37, Folder 416)
  - Ford Foundation Report, "Program Related Investments: A Different Approach to Philanthropy", 1974 (Box 37, Folder 417)
  - List of Materials in the Archives - Program-Related Investments, 1969-1987 (Box 37, Folder 418)
  - Format Handbook and Memoranda Regarding Program-Related Investments Procedure, 1984-1987 (Box 37, Folder 419)
  - MIT Workshops, 1990-1995 (Box 37, Folder 420)
  - Program-Related Investments Source, 1991 (Box 37, Folder 421)
  - PRI Workshop - Conference Materials, 1991 October (Box 37, Folder 422)
  - Worldwide Meeting on Development Finance in October 1995, 1994-1995 (Box 37, Folder 423)
- Subject Files, 1965-2003; 6
  The Ford Foundation defines subject files as records related to development, management, implementation, monitoring, assessment, evolution, and reflection upon foundation program strategies, issues, and grant-making initiatives. This series contains correspondence, press materials, reports, trip files, and meeting materials from projects and initiatives that Michael Lipsky was involved in. This series contains material that is complementary to other series in the collection.
  - State Fiscal Analysis Initiative - Mexican American Legal Defense and Educational Fund (MALDEF) - Correspondence and Press Releases, 2000 (Box 38, Folder 424)
    Grant Number: 980-1683
  - Institute on Innovation, John F. Kennedy School of Government, Harvard University Proposal, 2000 (Box 38, Folder 425)
  - Ralph Lysyshy, Forum of Federations, 2000 October 25 (Box 38, Folder 426)
  - National Whistleblower Center, 2000 September (Box 38, Folder 427)